

ADEAN RESSAN LADIA

Full-Stack Developer / Systems Architect

Python

Flask, Django, Django REST, etc.

PHP

Laravel, Codelgniter, Slim, etc.

Java

Native Android, etc.

JavaScript

NodeJS, TypeScript, Vue, Angular, Riot, etc.

HTML5, CSS3

SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Material, etc.

Relational Databases / SQL

MySQL, PSQL, MS SQL, SQLite

No-SQL DBMS

MongoDB, CouchDB, Neo4J, Elasticsearch, etc.

Cloud Platforms

Azure, AWS, Digital Ocean, Vultr, etc.

Container Technology

Docker and Kubernetes

Mobile and Desktop Framework

Cordova, Native Script, Electron, etc.

Contact Me at:

adeanladia0129@gmail.com +63 928 3078 936

narraressan.github.io/narra linkedin.com/in/adean-ladia-930b2012a

ABOUT ME

I started my professional career in 2014. Since then, I have experienced working in various designations such as backend lead developer, frontend developer, and lead architect.

With my 4-year industry experience, I can design and implement scalable, maintainable, and pragmatic applications with least supervision.

My passion is programming. Solving problems constantly and devising efficient ways to improve people's lives is my job and success.

EXPERIENCE

2018 – Present

Intermediate Level – Full-time Contract

Backend Developer Detail Tech Ph.

www.detailonline.com Davao City, Philippines

Designated Task

- Design and implement scale-able Docker swarms & Kubernetes nodes for collective web crawling.
- Lead a small backend team to create and deploy docker images on Azure Kubernetes
- Create and manage Restful services written in NodeJs, Python Flask, and Python Django REST.

2016 - 2018

Junior Level – Full-time Contract

Backend Developer Samatosa Software Developer Corp.

www.samatosa.com Davao City, Philippines

Designated Task

- Maintain and enhance RESTful microservices for web crawlers deployed in Azure cloud servers.
- Create web crawling strategies using python and node frameworks to gather price, images, compare image match, and overall online product footprint.
- Setup cloud databases with MongoDB, CouchDB, MySQL, Elasticsearch, and PSQL.

2017 - 2019

Intermediate Level – Project Based Contract

Full Stack Developer Corduro Inc.

www.corduro.com

Southlake, TX 76092, United States

Designated Task

- Convert PSD to web / mobile interfaces. And create web applications depending on client specifics.
- Create backend microservices and integrate 3rd party APIs and payment gateways (Stripe & Paypal)
- Add and maintain features for existing applications written with AngularJs and VueJs. And, conduct health check on Digital Ocean droplet servers.

2018

Oct – Dec

Intermediate Level – Part-time Contract Backend Developer The Resides Group

ph.linkedin.com/company/the-resides-group

New York, NY

Designated Task

Design and implement new backend features with NodeJS and conduct bug fixing and system maintenance with existing Laravel projects.

2016 June – Oct

Full-time Contract

Lecturer and Student Records Sys. Admin ACLC – AMA Computer Learning College

www.aclcgensan.net

General Santos City, Philippines

Designated Task

- Conduct lectures on Basic to Advance Programming, DBMS, and Automated Testing for IT and Com Sci students.
- Maintain and develop features for the school's student I.S., manage automated database backup, optimize database access, and report generation.

FREELANCE PROJECTS

2018

Dropscraper

Oct – Dec

Full Stack Developer www.dropscraper.com

Dec 2018

Dream Big Media Inc.DATO CMS Consultant

Sept 2018

Bricks App

Frontend Developer & Consultant

www.bricksapp.io

Jul 2018

TIO Listing Chatbot

Back-end Architect & Consultant

June 2018

T-Shirt Platform Project

Back-end Architect & Consultant

2018

Bookd

Feb - March

Database Architect & Consultant

www.bookd.online

2017 Sept – Dec

TemplateTed

Full Stack Developer www.templateted.com

2017 BHS: Biological Health Services

June – Aug Full stack Developer

www.biologicalhealthservices.com.au

2017 Skedluxe

March - May Full stack Developer

Feb 2017 Maestro

UI/UX Designer

2016 Poadis

Front-end Developer www.poadis.com

2016 LigiDex - 1st SOX Startup Challenge Winner

By Crazy Ideas

Coach and App Architect

2016 Aerial Surveillance with IP Cam on Commercialized Quad copters

MSU-GSC BSEE Thesis

Programmer

2016 Online Election & Mobile Monitoring

MSU-GSC BA&A Student Elections Lead Programmer & Architect

2016 Mobits

IT Week Official Mobile App Programmer & Appointed Mentor

2015 – 2016 Tekkies

Programmer & Animator

2015 OMANSS Mobi

IT Week Official Mobile App

Programmer

2015 Howe Insurance Services, LTD

2D Animator

2014 – 2015 FX

Programmer & Animator

2013 - 2014 BAGWIS – Official School's Publication

Mindanao State University, GSC

Layout Artist/ Videographer/ Animator/ Website In charge

EDUCATION

2012 – 2016 BS Information Technology - Database Track

Mindanao State University

Tambler, General Santos City, Philippines

Internship Web Developer | MSU, GSC

Capstone Project WebRTC Integrated Communication System and Respondent Locator

- Adviser: Valdimir Oliva, Phd

ANSHS: Billing and Fee Collection System

Software Eng. Project - Adviser: Laiza L. Limpin, MIT

- Academic Special Muslim Grant

Scholarships - SWEEP

- PPSS

- Civil Service Exam Passer – Professional Level (2016)

Awards & Eligibility - PSITS: Outstanding I.T. Student of the Year (2016)

- IT Engineer of the Year (2016)